A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Homes, Series I FA318
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Seal Harbor, ME
  - Seal Harbor - Radio Station, 1930-1932 (Box 105, Folder 1050)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. requests government to consider moving radio station to preserve beauty of proposed road. Plan studied by naval officials. Sent to Congress for action. Station moved from Otter Creek to Schoodic Point in 1933. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Horace M. Albright, Arthur Woods, Arno B. Cammerer.
  - Seal Harbor - Radio Station, 1928-1930 (Box 105, Folder 1051)
  - Seal Harbor - Radio Station - Purchase of Sargent Lot, 1932-1933 (Box 105, Folder 1052)
  - Seal Harbor - Radio Station, 1932-1935 (Box 105, Folder 1053)
  - Seal Harbor - S. F. Ralston - Correspondence, 1924-1934 (Box 106, Folder 1054)
    Seal Harbor superintendent. Pay of employees. Changes on estate. Care of property. Roads. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments on estate. Retirement. Pension. Death. Salary. Gifts. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., S. F. Ralston, Robert W. Gumbel, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Seal Harbor - S. F. Ralston - Mrs. S. F. Ralston, 1926-1931 (Box 106, Folder 1055)
    Made requests for aid. Declined.
  - Seal Harbor - S. F. Ralston - Long Pond Lodge and Road, 1924-1929 (Box 106, Folder 1056)
    Built for superintendent.
  - Seal Harbor - S. F. Ralston - Correspondence, 1935-1953 (Box 106, Folder 1057)
  - Seal Harbor - S. F. Ralston - Salary and Gifts, 1925-1943 (Box 106, Folder 1058)
    Salary increases. Gifts for special work done. Annual gift for vacation expenses. Totals of gifts. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., S. F. Ralston.
  - Seal Harbor - S. F. Ralston - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 106, Folder 1059)
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company, 1913-1930 (Box 107, Folder 1060)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr., and other Seal Harbor friends form realty company, to handle purchases and sales in their interest. George L. Stebbins was the largest stockholder. In 1926, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. bought up entire company. Discussion of land owned by company. Changes in directors. Correspondents include Edward K. Dunham, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George L. Stebbins, Serenus B. Rodick, Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Bracy Cove Purchase, 1924-1927 (Box 107, Folder 1061)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. buys land from Realty Company. Used for Swimming Pool.
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Plan for Financing, 1921-1922 (Box 107, Folder 1062)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. underwrites company's operations.
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Pritchard and Tower Properties, 1921-1925 (Box 107, Folder 1063)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. financed purchase of both pieces for Realty Company.
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Purchase of Realty Company Stock, 1926 (Box 107, Folder 1064)
    Purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in 1926.
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Mrs. William T. Sedgwick Fund, 1921-1923 (Box 107, Folder 1065)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $5,000 to $50,000 fund for widow.
    See also Box 103, Folder 1019 for Sedgwick Property.
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company, 1925-1946 (Box 107, Folder 1066)
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Sale to G. H. Montague, 1930-1946 (Box 107, Folder 1067)
    Sale. Restrictions on land. Controversy between Dr. J. B. Murphy and G. H. Montague.
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Sale to William A. Wirtz, 1939 (Box 107, Folder 1068)
    Sale of land once owned by Realty Company.
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Transfer to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1936 (Box 107, Folder 1069)
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Transfer to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Liquidation, 1925-1940 (Box 107, Folder 1070)
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Sales of Various Lots by Company, 1926-1931 (Box 107, Folder 1071)
  - Seal Harbor - Realty Company - Sale of Hillcrest Cottage, 1928 (Box 107, Folder 1072)
  - Seal Harbor - Red Cross District Nurse, 1918-1934 (Box 107, Folder 1073)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s annual contributions to Red Cross work at Seal Harbor. Special gifts to aid nurse. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. Edward K. Dunham, Miss C. Nelson.
  - Seal Harbor - Red Cross - Pledge, 1928-1933 (Box 107, Folder 1074)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes $12,000 toward cost of house for Red Cross work.
  - Seal Harbor - Richardson Farm, 1919-1931 (Box 108, Folder 1075)
    Search for safe milk supply for summer residents. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. offers to aid milk producer financially to ensure proper conditions. Fire destroys equipment. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and others lend further funds. Edward K. Dunham and others financed sanitary dairy farm on island. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. assumed some of the debt. Richardson, the farmer, had difficulty paying off debt. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and other creditors made several adjustments in principal. Debt finally paid off. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Edward K. Dunham, Mrs. Edward K. Dunham, P. S. Richardson, D. H. McAlpin.
  - Seal Harbor - Richardson Farm, 1932-1944 (Box 108, Folder 1076)
  - Seal Harbor - Relocation of Reef Point Plants, 1956-1961 (Box 108, Folder 1077)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. financed transfer of Beatrix Farrand's gardens at Reef Point to Asticou Terrace and Thuya lodge area. Also work on roads to Thuya Lodge. Payments completed by Estate. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles K. Savage.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - General, 1931-1958 (Box 109, Folder 1078)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made first subscription toward road building in 1913. Gave $250 to George L. Stebbins. Also began his own extension road work that year. Stebbins supervised early road work for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Gradual extension of road network. Relations with builders, local authorities. Comments on roads. Cooperation with National Park authorities. Letters of appreciation for roads. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George L. Stebbins, Charles O. Heydt, George B. Dorr, Paul Simpson, Charles K. Savage.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - General, 1924-1931 (Box 109, Folder 1079)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - General, 1912-1924 (Box 109, Folder 1080)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Beech Hill Road, 1931-1934 (Box 109, Folder 1081)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr's interest and aid.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Data Regarding Cost of Roads, 1928 (Box 109, Folder 1082)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Eagle Lake Road, North of Tea House, 1932 (Box 109, Folder 1083)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Change in Eagle Lake Road, 1933-1934 (Box 109, Folder 1084)
    Construction to make road safe. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s approval.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Hearing in Washington, 1924 (Box 109, Folder 1085)
    Secretary of Interior hearing on road building. Thomas M. Debevoise attended for John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - L. B. Hoyt, 1928-1932 (Box 109, Folder 1086)
    Hiring of engineer for road construction. Release.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Miscellaneous Pledges, 1932-1937 (Box 109, Folder 1087)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Publication of Path Map, 1929-1934 (Box 109, Folder 1088)
    Path map committee. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William J. Turner, Charles H. Grandgent.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Road at Head of Somes Sound, 1930-1936 (Box 109, Folder 1089)
    Straightening road. Selling land to Richard W. Hale for access to new road.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Turn Around at Wallover, 1931-1934 (Box 109, Folder 1090)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s deed of Turn Around to Mt. Desert. Town paid for one-half cost.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Wildwood Farms at Bubble Pond Road, 1915-1921 (Box 109, Folder 1091)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to road upkeep.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - New Barr Hill Road, 1920-1922 (Box 109, Folder 1092)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Appreciation, 1926-1959 (Box 110, Folder 1093)
    Letters of appreciation and replies.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Amphitheatre Road, 1929-1933 (Box 110, Folder 1094)
    Building road. Pledges. $124,387.55 total. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Aunt Betty's Pond Road, 1929-1935 (Box 110, Folder 1095)
    Constructing road. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest and aid. Corresondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arno B. Cammerer, S. F. Ralston, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Aunt Betty's Pond Road - Pledge, July 16, 1929 (Box 110, Folder 1096)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Automobile Road, 1929-1930 (Box 110, Folder 1097)
    Reports and discussion of road location in Acadia National Park. Attempt to get road built with Public Works Administration (PWA) funds, unsuccessful. Wildwood Farm Road legal status. Road from farm to Gorge. Mt. Kebo road tract to government. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arno B. Cammerer, Serenus B. Rodick, Frederick Law Olmsted.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Automobile Road, 1936 (Box 110, Folder 1098)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Automobile Road, 1934-1936 (Box 110, Folder 1099)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Barr Hill, 1932-1939 (Box 110, Folder 1100)
    Authorization for work. Barr Hill, Day Mountain. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Robert W. Gumbel, S. F. Ralston.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Barr Hill - Pledges, 1931-1933 (Box 110, Folder 1101)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Bridle Path, 1917-1932 (Box 110, Folder 1102)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s desire to build road. Mr. Abbot's objection. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to Bridle Path Fund of Northeast Harbor. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles W. Eliot, Edwin H. Abbot, J. P. Tunis.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Bridle Path from Bar Harbor, 1920-1922 (Box 110, Folder 1103)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Brown Mountain - C. D. Joy, 1919-1932 (Box 111, Folder 1104)
    Terms for road bulding. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s satisfaction. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Chancy Joy, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Brown Mountain - C. D. Joy - Division B, 1919-1920 (Box 111, Folder 1105)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Brown Mountain - C. D. Joy - Gate House, 1928-1929 (Box 111, Folder 1106)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Brown Mountain - C. D. Joy - Roads from Brown Mountain, 1921-1924 (Box 111, Folder 1107)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Bubble Pond, Eagle Lake Road, 1927-1955 (Box 111, Folder 1108)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Bubble Pond, Eagle Lake Road, 1926-1927 (Box 111, Folder 1109)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Bubble Pond, Eagle Lake Road - Pledges, 1927-1928 (Box 111, Folder 1110)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Bubble Pond, Eagle Lake Road - Payments on Pledges, 1928-1929 (Box 111, Folder 1111)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Cadillac Mountain Road, 1928-1935 (Box 111, Folder 1112)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest. Relocation and construction. Dedication. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s desire that major credit for road to be given to National Park Service. Contribution for dedication ceremony. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arno B. Cammerer.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Carriage Road East of Eagle Lake, 1925-1929 (Box 111, Folder 1113)
    Plans to construct road, build fishway. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest. Pledge. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Carriage Road East of Eagle Lake - Pledges, 1928 (Box 111, Folder 1114)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Carriage Road West Side of Eagle Lake, 1925-1927 (Box 111, Folder 1115)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge for clearing area. Other pledges. Sections 2, 4-5, 6. Correspondents include A. H. Lynam, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Carriage Road West Side of Eagle Lake, 1924-1926 (Box 111, Folder 1116)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Carriage Road West Side of Eagle Lake - Section 2, 1925-1926 (Box 111, Folder 1117)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Carriage Road West Side of Eagle Lake - Sections 3-5, 1926-1927 (Box 111, Folder 1118)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Carriage Road West Side of Eagle Lake - Section 6, 1926-1927 (Box 111, Folder 1119)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - A. E. Clement, 1916-1918 (Box 112, Folder 1120)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - A. E. Clement - Road from Stable to Long Pond, 1922-1924 (Box 112, Folder 1121)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - A. E. Clement - Commission, Statement, 1919-1923 (Box 112, Folder 1122)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - A. E. Clement - General Correspondence, 1918-1925 (Box 112, Folder 1123)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - A. E. Clement - Jordan Dam Bridge to Lookout, 1920-1921 (Box 112, Folder 1124)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - A. E. Clement - Barr Hill Road, 1913-1920 (Box 112, Folder 1125)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - A. E. Clement - Long Pond Crossing, 1918 (Box 112, Folder 1126)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - A. E. Clement - East End Asticon - Jordan Pond, 1920 (Box 112, Folder 1127)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Ernest B. Dane - Correspondence, 1925-1949 (Box 112, Folder 1128)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s desire to provide a less winding road to park. Mr. Dane's objection to relocation. 1938 exchange of 2.91 acres. Mr. Dane's death. Disposal of property. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ernest B. Dane, Helen Dane.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Ernest B. Dane - Correspondence, 1942-1948 (Box 112, Folder 1129)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Ernest B. Dane - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 112, Folder 1130)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Ernest B. Dane - Wildwood Farm, 1948 (Box 112, Folder 1131)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Eagle Lake, Jordan Pond Roads, 1926-1928 (Box 113, Folder 1132)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Eagle Lake, Jordan Pond Roads, 1924-1925 (Box 113, Folder 1133)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Eagle Lake, Jordan Pond Roads, 1922-1924 (Box 113, Folder 1134)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Eagle Lake, Jordan Pond Roads, 1922 (Box 113, Folder 1135)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Government Appropriations - Construction, 1937-1938 (Box 113, Folder 1136)
    Discussion of government road building, gates for park considered. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Gano Dunn, Arno B. Cammerer, Thomas C. Vint.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Government Appropriations - Construction, 1930-1935 (Box 113, Folder 1137)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - 1931 Program - Withdrawal of Offer (Box 113, Folder 1138)
    Request to withdraw offer to construct roads totaling $4,000,000 because of certain summer residents' objections to plans. Public response, most urging construction. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Francis G. Peabody.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - 1931 Program - Withdrawal of Offer (Box 113, Folder 1139)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - 1931 Program - Withdrawal of Offer - Raymond B. Fosdick's Letters (Box 113, Folder 1140)
    Public opinion on road plans. Reasons for withdrawal of offer. Letters acknowledged by Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - 1931 Program - Withdrawal of Offer - Raymond B. Fosdick's Letters (Box 113, Folder 1141)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - 1931 Program - Withdrawal of Offer - Letters Acknowledged by Raymond B. Fosdick (Box 114, Folder 1142)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - 1931 Program - Withdrawal of Offer - Mr. Sherman, Bar Harbor Times (Box 114, Folder 1143)
    Newspaperman thinks public should be better informed.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - June 1930 Offer and Withdrawal (Box 114, Folder 1144)
    Lists of letters, May 1934. Letters for and against road. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - June 1930 Offer and Withdrawal - Letter to National Park Service, January 19, 1931 (Box 114, Folder 1145)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - June 1930 Offer and Withdrawal - Offer to Government, June 27, 1930 (Box 114, Folder 1146)
    Offer of three tracts of land to government.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - June 1930 Offer and Withdrawal - Revised Letter to Government (Box 114, Folder 1147)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - June 1930 Offer and Withdrawal - Secretary Dixon's Letter Postponing Withdrawal, July 29, 1932, 1930-1932 (Box 114, Folder 1148)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Agreement with Government, 1933 (Box 114, Folder 1149)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s relationship with the Deparment of Interior. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. will construct roads but without any binding obligation to government. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ray Lynam Wilbur.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Government Road Construction, 1939-1955 (Box 114, Folder 1150)
    Federal government finances three bridges. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest. Comments on delays in program. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s aid. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Horace M. Albright, Newton B. Drury, Arno B. Cammerer.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Government Road Construction, 1938-1939 (Box 114, Folder 1151)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Government Road Construction - Mr. Dorr's Property, 1937-1939 (Box 114, Folder 1152)
    Dorr Foundation. Proposed gift of land to government. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s comments on transactions.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Government Road Construction, 1940-1946 (Box 115, Folder 1153)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Government Road Construction, 1940 (Box 115, Folder 1154)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Government Road and Bridge Construction, 1947-1951 (Box 115, Folder 1155)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Government Road and Bridge Construction - Possible New Park Entrance, 1947-1949 (Box 115, Folder 1156)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge, gift.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Icy Hill Road, 1939-1942 (Box 115, Folder 1157)
    Relocation of road. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest and contribution, roughly 20 percent. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, Jay Downer, Paul D. Simpson.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Icy Hill Road, 1933-1939 (Box 115, Folder 1158)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Jordan Pond Road Relocation, 1928-1934 (Box 115, Folder 1159)
    Widening of Jordan Pond-Eagle Lake Road in park. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s offer to pay part of cost. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Paul D. Simpson.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Jordan Pond Road Relocation - Copy of Deed, 1933-1934 (Box 115, Folder 1160)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Jordan Pond Road Relocation - Right of Way Deed, 1933-1955 (Box 115, Folder 1161)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Jordan Pond Road Abandonment - Right of Way, 1933-1935 (Box 116, Folder 1162)
    Duties and liabilities of grantor and grantee. Abandonment of Jordan Pond Road. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. donated deed of right-of-way of abandoned road in town of Mt. Desert to government. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, A. H. Lynam, C. D. Joy, S. F. Ralston.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Jordan Pond Road Abandonment - Right of Way, 1932-1933 (Box 116, Folder 1163)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Jordan Sargent Mountain - Horse Road, 1924-1926 (Box 116, Folder 1164)
    Specifications for road. Construction. A. E. Clement. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledges, satisfaction. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. H. Lynam.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Jordan Sargent Mountain - Horse Road, 1922-1924 (Box 116, Folder 1165)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Jordan Sargent Mountain - Horse Road - Pledges, 1922-1926 (Box 116, Folder 1166)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge $125,000 for road construction.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Bishop Lawrence's Committee, 1927-1932 (Box 116, Folder 1167)
    Committee for development of island. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s objection to formulating a general plan for development of park. Corresondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Gist Blair, Dave H. Morris.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Jordan Pond Road Underpass, 1929-1932 (Box 116, Folder 1168)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. builds pass under highway.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Bishop Lawrence's Committee, 1927-1928 (Box 116, Folder 1169)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Little Harbor Brook, 1918-1919 (Box 116, Folder 1170)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Little Harbor Brook - Clement Contracts, 1918-1921 (Box 116, Folder 1171)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Little Harbor Brook - Clement Payments, 1919-1920 (Box 116, Folder 1172)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Walter Kidde, 1929-1931 (Box 117, Folder 1173)
    Authorization for work. Correspondents include Walter Kidde.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road - Payments for Eagle Lake Road, 1924 (Box 117, Folder 1174)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road - Payments for Eagle Lake Road, 1922-1924 (Box 117, Folder 1175)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road - Pledges for Motor Road, 1926-1928 (Box 117, Folder 1176)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road - Right of Way, 1927-1933 (Box 117, Folder 1177)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road - Pledges for Motor Road, 1922-1925 (Box 117, Folder 1178)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road - Sections 8-9, 1925-1926 (Box 117, Folder 1179)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road - Wages, 1924-1925 (Box 117, Folder 1180)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road - Mr. Walls, 1924-1925 (Box 117, Folder 1181)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road, 1927 (Box 117, Folder 1182)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Road, 1926-1927 (Box 117, Folder 1183)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Roads - Second Section, 1924-1928 (Box 118, Folder 1184)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Roads - Second Section, 1924 (Box 118, Folder 1185)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Roads - Third Section, 1924-1925 (Box 118, Folder 1186)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Roads - Fourth Section, 1924-1926 (Box 118, Folder 1187)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Roads - Fifth Section, 1925 (Box 118, Folder 1188)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Roads - Sixth Section, 1925-1926 (Box 118, Folder 1189)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Motor Roads - Seventh Section, 1925-1926 (Box 118, Folder 1190)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Mitchell Jordan Stream Road, 1915-1917 (Box 118, Folder 1191)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Newport Mountain Route through Palmer Lots, 1948-1956 (Box 118, Folder 1192)
    Opposition to rerouting of road by Mr. Potter Palmer. Attempts to have him reconsider. Attempts to purchase land, acquire property by condemnation proceedings. Finally Mrs. Palmer agreed to donate strip of land to government. Wanted to reroute road because of view. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. H. Lynam, Potter Palmer, Arno B. Cammerer, Dave H. Morris, C. C. Little, Harold L. Ickes, Newton B. Drury, Chauncey McCormick, N. Morris.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Newport Mountain Route through Palmer Lots, 1941-1948 (Box 118, Folder 1193)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Newport Mountain Route through Palmer Lots, 1934-1941 (Box 118, Folder 1194)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Newport Mountain Route through Palmer Lots, 1931-1933 (Box 118, Folder 1195)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads -Newport Mountain Road - Atwater Kent, 1939-1946 (Box 119, Folder 1196)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in purchase of land to construct road. Pledge. Atwater Kent gives $21,500 for purchase of Bliss Field. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Atwater Kent, Arno B. Cammerer.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads -Newport Mountain Road - Atwater Kent, 1937-1939 (Box 119, Folder 1197)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - North Eagle Lake - Hull Cove, 1927-1932 (Box 119, Folder 1198)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest. Constructing road. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - North Eagle Lake - Hull Cove - Pledges, 1927-1928 (Box 119, Folder 1199)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s offer to trustees. Regarding deed of land from Town of Bar Harbor.
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - North Eagle Lake - Hull Cove - Deed of Land from Bar Harbor, 1921-1928 (Box 119, Folder 1200)
  - Seal Harbor - Roads - Ocean Drive, 1933-1935 (Box 119, Folder 1201)